Well, why Russia the Baltics And why
Ну зачем Россия Прибалтика А зачем
Russia and Ukraine Maybe you
Россия и Украина Может быть вы там
will move there to Poland or Germany Why
перейдёте в Польшу или в Германию Зачем
Russia and Ukraine maybe yes, because
Россия и Украина может быть да ну потому
we are one people, at
что мы один народ хотя
least you are who you are Russia is a
бы вы это кто у вас Россия
multinational country Buryats Chechens
многонациональная страна буряты чеченцы
What kind of people are they with the
Какой это один народ с
Ukrainians  Hello Hello,
украинцами Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
where are you from
откуда с
Russia?
России город
Well, it doesn’t matter. It’s important. It’s just interesting. I’m
Ну неважно Это важно Интересно просто я
from Jurmala, Latvia. Yes, I see that. What are
из юрмалы Латвии Да я вижу что А о чём
you talking about
вы говорите
here? I’m asking people from Russia what
тут я у людей из России спрашиваю что
they know about
они знают про
Latvia. Well, this is a former
Латвию Ну это бывшая
republic of the Soviet
республика Советского
Union.
Союза
Well, we lived in Lithuania
Так ну мы жили в Литве
Yes, in Riga I don’t know, maybe my parents
Да в Риге Я не знаю может мои родители
were in Riga But
были в Риге Но
this was back in Soviet times,
это это ещё в советские времена конец
probably the end of the eighties,
наверно восьмидесятых годов
what else do you know about Latvia? Well, I don’t know anything about Latvia. I know about
Ну я не знаю Латвии ничего Я знаю про
Lithuania, but about the Lithuanians, they’re
Литву но про литовцев что
good, honest and
хороший честный иче
nothing else.  I can what can I say I have
тби ничего не могу что я могу сказать Я
never seen How do you How do you in
никогда не видел А как вы Как вы вот в
Russia feel about the fact that Latvia
России относитесь к тому что Латвия
Lithuania Estonia they joined NATO Well what
Литва Эстония они вступили в НАТО Ну что
else could they
им ещё оставалось
do? You have it on YouTube
делать это у вас там это на ютуберу
Yes, it was shown from the previous video
Да с предыдущем ролик
So what if  Yes,
показывал Так и что сли да
I know that somehow you and the Lithuanians have
Я знаю что как-то у вас с литовцами
something, I don’t know how they didn’t
как-то что-то не знаю как это не
understand that somehow everything was
понимали что там как-то всё нормально
always normal with us.
всегда у нас
And what was not regulated with us with the
ли А что у нас было не отрегулировано с
Lithuanians? Well, how about horses’ heads they called you
литовцами Ну как о лошадями головами вас
that's where you heard this, you
вот где вы такое
knew each other, stayed there, people lived there,
знакомы оставались там жили там люди как
well, maybe it was just everyday life,
бы ну это может быть просто бытового
maybe you know, like this. This is the first time I
может быть знаете как бы так вот Впервые
heard that the Lithuanians and I had
слышу чтобы у нас с литовцами были
some kind of graters.
какие-то
Yes, how much do you have a communal apartment
Да сколько у вас коммуналка
now? What do all Russians ask about communal apartments?
сейчас что все россияне про коммуналку
Well, how normal are you there? It’s really
спрашивают Ну как вы там вообще
a feeling that
нормально такое ощ такое ощущение что вы
in Russia, in short, you give your entire salary to a
короче в России всю зарплату отдаёте на
communal apartment, but for you a communal apartment is a
коммуналку бо для вас коммуналка - это
feeling that it’s all nothing. Well,
такое ощущение что это всё нет ничего Ну
only a small part. Well, what
маленькую часть только Ну так а какая
difference does it make?
разни просто Что у вас евро вас всё в
euro Well, those acquaintances who come to us, let’s
евро Ну те знакомые которые к нам
say in Russia, it’s still there about
приезжают допустим в Россию это ещё там
10 years ago, they kind of told the truth
лет 10 назад они как бы ну правду матку
there and there that everything is
говорили там как там Что там всё по
strictly according to the counters. But with you, not everything is according to
строго А у вас не всё по
the counters, let’s say by scam 400 rubles for a replacement
счётчикам допустим по скам 400 руб заме
according to the cash register Yes  Well, you know, the difference is
по счм Да ну так понимаете разница-то
different, how much to pay there is 400 rubles or
разная сколько платить там 400 руб или
there is 100 euros or 200 euros, how much do you
там 100 евро или 200 евро сколько там
pay there, is there a difference or not What do you
платите это есть разница или нет Как вы
think again, what did you pay 400
считаете ещё раз за что Вы заплатили 400
rubles for, well, according to the meter, yes, how much do you pay for light
руб ну по счётчику сказа Да вы за свет
for gas?  they paid it, well,
за газ сколько Вы заплатили это ну по
different different month different
Разно разный месяц по-разному
4 for water I yes I say this is
4 за воду я да я говорю это это
electricity
электроэнергия
this is gas this is water cold hot
это это газ это вода холодная горячая
water here is a communal apartment - this is a separate housing and communal services
вода вот коммуналка - это отдельная ЖКХ
there, like for heating for Well,
там типа за отопление за Ну и у нас ну
damn for water how much water did I use?
блин за воду сколько воды использовал
that's how much the electricity and gas paid you at the beginning of the
столько и заплатил свет газ вы в начале
conversation you said about NATO you are glad that
разговора сказали про НАТО вы рады что
you joined NATO and that
вы вступили в НАТО и что да на нас
now you are not attacking us like you are attacking
теперь вы на нас не нападает как на
Ukraine. Why do we
Украину А зачем вы нам нужны
need you? I don’t know why you need Ukraine Well, that’s
Я не знаю зачем вам Украина нужна Ну это
a little different Latvia  Latvia and what and
немножко другое Латвия Латвия а что А
why is Ukraine different? Well, it’s a slightly
чем Украина другая Ну там немножко
different story
другая история
completely. Well, why should I tell you
совершенно Ну что м рассказывать вот вам
something all the time? Someone, you know all this very
постоянно что-то кто-то вы всё это
well and you yourself don’t know. Okay,
прекрасно знаете и сами не знаю Ладно
I think that the same thing is true, the Russians
что я я считаю что тоже самое россияне
tell me that we are all former  The republics
мне говорят что мы все бывшие Республики
should return to the USSR Well, why
должны вернуться в СССР Ну зачем
the Baltics
Прибалтике
Well, why Russia the Baltics And why
Ну зачем Россия Прибалтика А зачем
Russia and Ukraine Maybe you
Россия и Украина Может быть вы там
will go there to Poland or Germany Why
перейдёте в Польшу или в Германию Зачем
Russia and Ukraine maybe, well,
Россия и Украина может быть да ну пото
because we are one people, at
что мы один народ хотя
least you are who you are Russia is a
бы вы это кто у вас Россия
multinational country  Buryats Chechens
многонациональная страна буряты чеченцы
What kind of people are they with the Ukrainians? I
Какой это один народ с украинцами Я
say that we are Russians and Ukrainians. We are one
говорю что мы русские и украинцы Мы один
people. So Russia is not the country of
народ Так у вас Россия - это не страна
Russians, it is the country of all 666
русских это страна всех там 666
nationalities. Well, Russians are the titular
национальностей Ну русски это титульная
la No, no, you don’t have that in the Constitution,
ла Нету Нету такого у вас в Конституции
there is no titular nation, no need
нету титульной нации не надо
tell your UN there that once
рассказывать вот ваш ООН там что ещё раз
again look open open the Constitution of the
ещё раз смотри открой открой Конституцию
Russian
Российской
Federation Open the Constitution No open the
Феде Открой Конституцию Нет открой
Constitution of the Russian Federation and find
Конституцию Российской Федерации и найди
there that this is a state of Russians that the
там что это государство русских что
titular nation of Russians there is not a word like that,
титульная нация русских нету такого ни
well, we are not all Russia However, it
слова ну мы Россия не все Тем не ме там
says multinational people
сказано многонациональный народ
Russian Federation That's what it says from
Российской Федерации Вот Так сказано от
no Russians there,
никаких русских там
once again look again, let's do this then
нету ещ раз ещё раз смотри давай так то
look how you and the Ukrainians are one people
смотри как же вы с украинцами один народ
If you are a multinational country Tatars
Если вы многонациональная страна татары
Chechens Bashkor there are Yakuts Sakha Yes, Buryats
чеченцы башкор там якуты Саха Да буряты
want to say that Ukrainians do not live in
хоти сказать что украинцы не живут в
Russia, Ukrainians live in Germany
России украинцы в Германии живут
there is in Germany and what then is it one
есть в Германии т а что тогда это один
people they came 8 million Sorry Rabo
народ они приезжали 8 млн Извините рабо
Wait if if again if the Tajiks are
Подождите если если ещё раз если таджики
now 3 million Tajiks in Russia yes you are
сейчас 3 млн таджиков в России да Вы
one people No of course No and the Ukrainians
один народ Нет конечно Нет а украинцы
mean because they came one
значит из-за того что приехали один
people Yes the poet of us  not that we came there
народ Да поэт нас не то что приехали там
again, look again Russia is the
ещё раз смотри ещё раз Россия - это
country of what kind of
страна какого
people We are Russians, we are all Russians, you are
народа Мы россияне мы все россияне вы
Russians And we are Latvians and they are Ukrainians
россияне А мы мы латыши а они украинцы
Yes, you
Да вы
No ethnically, I say that ethnically you are
Нет этнически я говорю что этнически вы
already you have already developed some kind of demagoguery
уже вы уже развите демагогию какую-то
once again  since Russia is ethnically
ещё раз ещё раз Россия - это этнически
what kind of country is that Wait, I’m telling you
какая странам ту Погодите я вам говорю
about the Slavic peoples so Russia
про славянские народы на так Россия -
is a Slavic country or not Slavic
это Славянская страна или не Славянская
Slavic Yes no Russia is a
Славянская Да нет Россия - это
multinational country there are
многонациональная страна там есть
Slavs Turks Fino
славяне тюрки фино
Ugrians Mongolian Buryat There and so
Угры монгольско бурятские Там и так
on who doesn’t have a titular nation  you
дальше кто нету титульной нации у вас
are not there, well, show me, look, if
нету что ж выж Покажите смотри если у
you have a titular nation Show Yes, in the
вас есть титульная нация Покажите Да в
Constitution that you have a titular
Конституции что у вас указана титульная
nation And you show that you are Latvians, what kind of
нация А вы покажите что вы латыши что
people are they once again, once again in your
это за народ ещё раз ещё раз у вас в
Constitution there is no concept of a titular nation,
Конституции нету понятия титульная нация
we have passed in our Constitution  Latvia
прошли у нас в Конституции Латвии
is written that this is the state of the Latvian
написано что это государство латвийского
people, Latvians are that people And you And
народа латыши это что народ А у вас А у
you, it turns out you don’t have the Russians
вас да получается у вас нету у русских
don’t have their own state Russians like them
нету своего государст русские как они
people live without a state at times live in
люди без государства живут в раз живут в
different states Yes, for example, in Russia
разных государствах Да например в России
in Ukraine in Latvia in Germany  Also,
в Украине в Латвии в Германии Также и
Russians live in different states
русские они живут в разных государствах
Yes, in Russia in Latvia in Ukraine in
Да в России в Латвии в Украине в
Germany the Russians
Германии у Русский
yes yes the Chechens have their own
вот да да у чеченцев есть своё
state Yes the Chechen
государство Да Чеченская
Republic Chechen Republic wound the
республика Чеченская республика рана у
Buryats have their own state Open Yes
бурят есть своё государство Откройте Да
Open the Constitution of Chechnya Open the
Откройте Конституцию Чечни Откройте
Constitution of Buryatia Tatarstan and
Конституцию Бурятии Татарстан и
look first  article that this is a
посмотрите первая статья что это
democratic state Well, you’re lying and
демократическое государство Ну лжёте и
everything is wrong No, let me open it for you now,
всё во вре Нет давайте я вам сейчас
look, let’s take it now
открою смотрите давайте сейчас возьмём
Let’s take the Constitution, for example,
Давайте вот Конституцию например
Buryatia You haven’t read it You don’t know
бурятий Вы же не читали Вы же не знаете
anything about your country
про свою страну ничего
Yes, take the Constitution of any Republic of Russia
Да Конституцию любой Республики России
and you’ll
возьмёте и вы
go nuts
офигеете
like that Constitution  of the Republic of Buryatia
так так Конституция республики Бурятия
we read like this the first first article I
читаем так первая первая статья Я же
looked at Adygea also like I’m just a lawyer
смотрел адыгею также типа я просто юрист
by training
по образованию
constitutionalists here is the Constitution of
конституционалисты вот Конституция
the Republic of Buryatia article one
Республики Бурятии статья один
the Republic of Buryatia is a democratic
республика Бурятия есть демократическое
legal state a subject of the Russian
правовое государство субъект Российской
Federation the state is not correct Yes the
Федерации государство нет правильно Да
state once again I read
государство ещё раз ещё раз читаю ещё
again I read the Republic of Buryatia is
раз читаю Республика Бурятия есть
democratic legal state
демократическое правовое государство
comma subject of the Russian Federation is the
запятая субъект Российской Федерации это
same as the same
же как также
as the European Union The European Union is also a
как вот как Евросоюз Евросоюз - это тоже
Federation there are different states Poland the
Федерация там разные государства Польша
state France the state they are all
государство Франция государство они все
part of the federation in the European Union What does the
входят в федерацию в Евросоюз Что значит
word mean What does the word
слово Что значит слово
Federation mean Well, the federal structure
Федерация Ну федеративное устройство
Federation is a union in
Федерация - это союз по
Latin  so look, the fact is that the
латыни так вот смотрите Дело в том что
Russian Federation is made up of different
россий Федерацию составляют разные
states, for example the state of Buryatia,
государства например государство Бурятия
there is no such state where where where
там нет такого государства где где где
here Let's say the word of the state again, I'll tell you the
вот Давайте слово госуда ещё раз я тебе
word state in the constitution of
вот слово государство в конституции
the Republic of Buryatia, I read it to you,
республики Бурятия я тебе прочитал
the Republic of Buryatia is a democratic
республика Бурятия из демократическое
rule of law state, open it up, let's
правовое государство Вот открой давайте
you  there you read so and further that Open
вы там читаете так и дальше что Открой
Well, if you think that I’m deceiving Well,
Ну вот если ты думаешь что я обману Ну
what next? What’s next? What’s next? Tatarstan is
что дальше Дальше что Татарстан
the state of Buryatia, the state Yes,
государство Бурятия государство Да
the Republic of Adygea The state is a
Республика Адыгея Государство это
separate year,
отдельный года
and our district is even Jewish again, and the
амы округ у нас даже еврейский ещё раз а
Russians don’t have their own state, so
у русских нет своего государства вот
Buryatia is the state of Tatarstan
Бурятия - государство Татарстан
The state is our entire state,
Государство это всё наше государство чу
no, no, what are the problems? Why do something for some
Нет какие проблемы А зачем что-то
reason, where there is a Russian republic, it’s
отчего-то де где есть русская республика
all of Russia, it’s us, no, no, the
так это вся Россия это мы нет нет
Russian Federation is a Federation of
Российская Федерация это Федерация
different state entities, that’s
разных государственных субъектов вот и
all, let’s look. You’re Europeans,
всё давай посмотри Вот вы европейцы да
yes. Look further in  first article Yes,
Вот смотри дальше в первой статье Да вот
the Republic of Buryatia has its own
республика Бурятия имеет свою
Constitution legislation citizenship
Конституцию законодательство гражданство
state symbols territory
государственные символы территорию
state languages ​​system of
государственные языки систему
state power and local self-
государственной власти и местное
government that is, Buryatia is a
самоуправление то есть Бурятия - это
full-fledged
полноценное
state, not who you think you are
государство не вы кем себя считаете
Read read well, really, look, you
Прочитай прочитай ну реально смотри ты
realized that you got burned, yes you realized that I
понял что подгорел да ты понял что я
drove you  in the corner Yes, because you
тебя загнал в угол Да потому что у вас
Russians don’t have their own state Yes, the
русских нету своего государства Да вот у
Buryats Let’s look further there
бурято Давайте посмотрим дальше там
The Republic of Adygea The
Республика Адыгея
Constitution of
Конституция
the Republic of
Республики
Agea, for example,
агея например
let’s
да
open and now look at the first article
открываем и сейчас смотрим первая статья
there will be the same thing,
там будет тоже самое так
so now it will load for me with a
так сейчас загрузится у меня с
pin here is the constitution of the Republic of Adygea
пином вот конституция Республика Адыгея
so section  about article one The Republic of
так раздел о статья один Республика
Adygea Adygea is a democratic
Адыгея Адыгея является демократическим
legal state within the
правовым государством в составе
Russian Federation, you still see the
Российской Федерации всё снова видишь
state again. That is, you don’t understand,
государство То есть ты не понимаешь вам
uh, powder your brains, you haven’t even looked at
ээ запудрить мозги вы даже не посмотрели
your Constitution Constitution of the constituent entities of the
свою Конституцию Конституцию субъектов
Russian Federation Yes, this is not like, for
Российская Федерация Да это не как
example, Ukraine Yes, in Ukraine we
например вот Украина Да в Украина у нас
have  regions, this is all one country, you
есть области это всё одна страна у вас в
have different states in Russia, Buryatia
Россию входят разные государство Бурятия
- this state they have their own
- это государство у них есть своё
legislation, their state
законодательство своё государственные
symbols, their parliament and their own
символы свой парламент да свой
head of state, here is Tatarstan, the
руководитель государства вот Татарстан
state of the Republic of Adygea and these
государство республика адыгей и эти
states have made the Union of the Russian
государства сделали Союз Российскую
Federation, that is, just like for example the
Федерацию то есть так же как например
European Union  Yes, for example,
Европейский союз Да вот есть например
Poland Germany, they gave some functions
Польша Германия они некоторые функции
to uh Brussels center Yes, to Brussels, yes, that
ээ Брюссель центру Да в Брюссель да то
is, the same as Moscow, yes, that is,
есть так же как вот Москва да то есть
there is a state Yes, and there is Moscow, it’s just
Есть государство Да и есть Москва просто
Moscow that has taken over more
Москва она перетянула на себя больше
powers Yeah, so if we look
полномочий Угу Так вот если мы смотрим
at this European Union  Yes, there the
ээ этот Евросоюз Да там
democratic unification in the Russian
демократическое объединение в Российская
Federation is essentially
Федерация по сути
illegal from these states. Yes, they
ээ у этих государств незаконно Да
took away some of the functions and took them to the
отобрали часть функций и и забрали в
federal center. I didn’t understand that someone
федеральный центр не понял что у кого-то
was taken from these states from these Moscow, yes
брали у этих государств у этих Москва да
Moscow took away the functions from these states
Москва отобрала у этих государст сечас
right now. Yes, look, uh  Putin Yes, he
функции Да вот смотрите ээ Путин Да
decreed that in these
постановил указ чтобы в этих
states there would be no president, that
государствах не было президента чтобы э
these positions would be called differently, as they are,
назывались эти как они должности
Tatarstan resisted until the very
по-другому Татарстан до самого
last year, until last year, in my opinion,
последнего до прошлого года по-моему
Tatarstan also
тастан тоже
changed the name, renamed this
изменить переименовали переименовали эту
position to Rais, this is in Arabic like a
должность в Раис это по арабски типа
leader like that  we are what you we
руководитель вот так вот мы что вы мы
have we have that the Russian Federation
имеем мы имеем что Российская Федерация
is a union of different states and
- это союз разных государств и
subjects in this union
субъектов в этом созе
but not the
но не государства
Russian state look was the SR Yes look
русских смотрите был СР Да смотри
comrade Latvians lawyer I’ll tell you so it
товарищ латыши адвокат я вам скажу так
was the Soviet Union and Latvia is part of the
был Советский Союз и Латвия - это часть
Soviet Union and what was  done In the
Советского Союза и то что было сделано В
ninety-first year it was absolutely
девяносто первом году это было абсолютно
illegitimate according to all the norms and laws, you are
нелегитимное по всем нормам и законам вы
like Latvia is part of
как Латвия часть
Russia How much is Russia here, look again,
Росси Почём тут России смотри ещ раз
it means what the Soviet Union is, I explain the
значит что такое Советский Союз объясняю
Soviet Union included 15 different
в Советский Союз входило 15 разных
states Yes, once again Latvia was a
государств Да ещё раз Латвия была
separate state Ukraine was a
отдельным государством Украина была
separate state Russian
отдельным государством Российская
The Federation was Russian, more precisely, the
Федерация была Российская точнее
Russian Soviet Federative
Российская Советская Федеративная
Socialist Republic was a
Социалистическая Республика была
separate state in the Soviet Union,
отдельным государством в Советском Союзе
there were 15 different
было 15 разных
states, you understand, you are part of Russia, that’s
государств понимаешь вы часть России вот
all, no, once again you are confusing, look, in the
и всё нет ещ раз ты путаешь смотри в
Soviet
Советском
SSR there would have been Latvia, there really was
бы бы ССР а была Латвия правда была
Latvia, look who and who was
Латвия Смотрите кто не кто был
the leader of
руководителем
Russia  Who was
России Кто был в Советском Союзе
the head of the Russian federation of the FSR in the Soviet Union?
руководителем российской федера ФСР
Yeltsin, the Soviet Union was led by
Ельцин вот Советский Союз руководил
Gorbachev And in every country In every
Горбачёв А в каждой стране В каждом
state Yes, in Russia there was a leader
государстве Да в России был руководитель
Yeltsin and so on, why are you bothering me with noodles
Ельцин и так дальше что вы мне лапшу
in my ears which RSFSR are you,
мешаете на уши какой РСФСР вы что
stop Yeltsin, what was he led by not Ponya of the
стоп Ельцин чем руководил не Поня
Russian Soviet  Federative
российской Советской Федеративной
Socialist RSFSR
Социалистической РСФСР
Who was the first president of the USSR The first and
Кто был первым президентом СССР первым и
only president of the USSR was
единственным президентом СССР был
Gorbachev
Горбачёв
and once again
так ещё
Yeltsin was the head of the Supreme
раз Ельцин был руководителем Верховного
Council of the RSFSR
Совета РСФСР
Russian Soviet Federative
Российская Советская Федеративная
Which 15 republics were part of the USSR That
Какие 15 республик входили в СССР То
is, I have to list it for you But
есть я должен Вам перечислить Да вот
tell me, let it be Russian
скажи мне давай было Российская
Soviet Federative Socialist
Советская Федеративная Социалистическая
Republic  included Yes there was yes the RSFSR
Республика входила Да была да РСФСР Вот
That's who headed it before the collapse of the
вот кто её возглавлял перед развалом
Soviet
Советского
Union there were
Союза не было там
no there no the head the head once again the head of the
никаких нет глава глава ещё раз глава
Republic
Республики
was you understand it was the Soviet Union
был понимаете это был Советский Союз
so look again God what he is
поэтому е в ещё раз смотри Боже какой он
just what they are so this re mark was a
просто какие они так это ре марочка была
man Sorry  Although I don’t excuse you,
мужик Извини Хотя не извиняю
look, the
смотри
Russian Soviet Federative
в Российской Советской Федеративной
Socialist Republic had its own
Социалистической Республики была своя
Constitution, the Ukrainian Soviet
Конституция в украинской Советской
Constitution, it had its own leadership in
Конституция была своё руководство в
each Union Republic, each Union
каждой союзной республике каждая Союзная
Republic was separate, they had their own
республика была отдельным
Constitution, they had
у них была своя Конституция у них была
their own parliament, yes And these 15
своя свой парламент да И эти 15
states were included  into a union of different
государств входили в союз разных
states comrade Latvian republics and
государств товарищ Латыш республики и
what What is a republic of Soviet
что Что такое республика Советских
Socialist
Социалистических
Republics
Республик
good EU republic is not a state
хорошо ЕС республика это не государство
dari republic is not a state this is a
дари республика - это не государство это
republic this is a different structure comrade
республика это другое устройство товарищ
good here China now is the
хорошо вот Китай вот сейчас есть
People's Republic of China this is not a state this is the People's Republic of China
китайская народная республика это не
this is a state Yes
государство это КНР это государство Да
so
так
the republic Well, how was it a united
республика Ну как это было объединённое
general wait, then the People's
обще подожди то китайская народная
Republic of China, since it's a republic, that means it's not
республика раз республика значит это не
a state, that's what you said, well, a state, then why is the
государство это же ты говорил ну
Ukrainian
государство да то почему украинская
Soviet Socialist Republic
Советская Социалистическая Республика
not a state, but the People's
это не государство а китайская народная
Republic of China is a state Well, that's what
республика - это государство Ну так
Lenin did. Sorry, I didn't do it  this
сделал Ленин Извините я не делал этого
again,
ещё
let's open the Constitution for you,
давай давай откроем тебе Конституцию к
what are you going to, your days are numbered And you,
чему вы идёте ваши дни сочтены А вы это
let me open the Constitution for you now,
Давай я тебе сейчас Конституцию открою
look, the Constitution of the Ukrainian Soviet
смотри Конституция украинской Советской
Socialist
Социалистической
Republic, you will now look like this.
Республики ты сейчас посмотришь так
Why are you oppressing the Russian people of
Почему же вы угнетается русских людей
yours so so Latvia and what will you
ваши так так Латвии а а что вы нам
do to us  ugh yes You who need you
сделаете тьфу да Вы кому вы нужны
understand how it is look uh The
понимаете как это вот смотри ээ
Constitution of the Ukrainian Soviet
Конституция украинской Советской
Socialist Republic the first
Социалистической Республики первая
article of the Ukrainian Soviet
статья украинская Советская
Socialist Republic is a
Социалистическая Республика есть
Socialist national
Социалистическая всенародная
state that expresses And so
государство которое выражает И так
on there was a state and you take the
дальше было государство и ты возьмёшь
Constitution of each republic of the Soviet
Конституцию каждой республики Советского
Union it was said that it is a
Союза там было сказано что оно
state and now  about us Latvians We are
государство а теперь про нас латышей Мы
Latvians of our Latvia, we will do
латыши своей Латвии будем делать ээ то
what we think is necessary, we believe that the
что считаем нужным мы считаем что тут
Latvian language needs to be developed here. Yes,
нужно развивать латышский язык Да так
open Latvian schools, erect
открывать латышские школы ставить
monuments to Latvian national heroes
памятники латышским национальным героям
and don’t ask about it,
и не спрашивать об этом
who are your heroes, please? You live in
а кто ваши героите пожалуста Вы живёте в
Russia and it’s none of your business  what will we
России и не ваше дело что мы будем
do in Latvia, who will we honor, what languages ​​should we
делать в Латвии кого чтить какие языки
study, what writers and poets should we erect
изучать каких писателей и поэтов ставить
monuments, look, you Russians
памятники вы смотри вы русские
will figure it out, make your own at least a
разберитесь сделайте своё хотя бы
Russian state and then you’ll understand the NM, the
русское государство и в НМ тогда
Chechens have a state, the
государство есть у чеченцев государство
Buryats have a state, the Russians have a Tatars No
у бурятов есть у татар у русских Нет
There are different areas that  everyone,
Есть разные области которые всех да
for example, Tajiks, Chechens,
например таджиков чеченцев
Azerbaijanis, everyone who lives there Yes, the
азербайджанцев всех кто там проживает Да
Russian Republic is still a
русской Республики до сих пор Федерации
Russian Federation. The fact is that the Russians as an Ethnic group have
русский Дело в том что русские как Этнос
not matured to create a
не созрели к созданию
state on the territory where
государства на территории где проживают
Russians live, the state has always been made either by the
русские государство всегда делали либо
Germans. But either by the Ukrainians or by the
немцы Да вот либо украинцы да либо
Mongols.  then they organized
монголы Да кто-то им организовал
a state because the Russians as an ethnos
государстве потому что русские как Этнос
are still at the stage before the
находятся ещё на стадии до
state development of tribal,
государственного развития родоплеменных
let’s say, relations. Yes, the Russians not so
ээ скажем отношений Да русские не так
long ago emerged from the
давно вышли из
state of the first, as it is in Russian,
состояния перви как это по-русски
primarily communal Lada,
первично общинного Лада
building the
строя
Russians in those territories of this
русские на тех территориях вот этого
forest even as Herodotus wrote  were the
залесья ещё как геродот писал были
Andropharm tribe and now now the whole
андрофарм и сейчас сейчас всё
civilized society Yes, the ancient Persians, the
цивилизованное общество Да древние персы
Tajiks, Yes, the ancient Balts, the Latvians, the ancient
таджики Да древние Балты латыши древние
Slavs, the Ukrainians, Yes, they bring light to these
славяне украинцы Да они несут в этим
Russians. They bring light, they teach them how to
русским Они несут свет обучают их
wash their hands. Yes, your ancestors. Yes, and
научили мыть руки Да ваш предки Да ещё
look, even 100 years ago,
Посмотрите ещё 100 лет назад с вшами
Lenin had lice when he came.  to power Yes, he
ходили Ленин когда пришёл к власти Да он
said that we need to defeat lice
что сказал нужно победить вшей потому
because all of Russia had lice because
что вся Россия ходила вшивое потому что
lice Yes, and Typhus was In short, one of the
педикулёз Да и Тиф был Короче одним из
big scourges, don’t hang out with me like this, I
большим бичей не Зависай у меня такая я
have to program you further to
должен тебя про программировать дальше
weigh
развес
in a good position, he’s calling comrade Latvian,
на хорошей позе он зви товарищ Латыш всё
look again  undercut how they are you
смотрите ещё раз подрез как они вы
Latvians You are there You are there You must
латыши Вы там Вы там Вы должны незаконно
have left illegally You are part of Russia and you are there schools
вышли вы часть России а вы там школы
monuments language
памятники язык овит
all water and rich life Yes
все водную и богатую жизнь да
Latvians Lithuanians Estonians Break away from the
латыши литовцы эстонцы Оторвались от
Soviet Union among the first and
Советского Союза одними из первых да
were able to quickly integrate into the Western
смогли бегом интегрироваться в западные
Western community and live better  better
Западное сообщество и живут лучше лучше
than this Russia, they always begin to
чем вот эта Россия они начинают всегда
compare the Baltic countries with Europe,
сравнивать ээ страны балтии с Европой
that people from there go to Germany
что вот люди оттуда выезжают в Германию
because there is poverty there,
потому что там э бедность
not there poverty, it’s just that in Germany there is
не там бедность просто в Германии
wealth, it’s just those countries that were
богатство просто те страны которые были
in the Soviet Union, they were poor from this Soviet Union and
в совке они были бедные из этого Совка и
when people escaped  from this Erma they
когда люди вырвались из этого Ерма они
began to develop If we look at Latvia
стали развиваться Если мы смотрим Латвия
Lithuania Estonia now live better than
Литва Эстония живут сейчас лучше чем
Russia better than Ukraine Belarus And so
Россия лучше чем Украина Белорусь И так
on Because they moved faster to the
дальше Потому что они быстрее пошли в
Western Vector of development faster Yes,
Западный Вектор развития быстрее вот Да
they live worse than Germany and Britain
они живут хуже Германии и Британии
because they are 100 years behind there
потому что они отстают там на лет 100
because of this Russian Empire of the
из-за вот этой Российской империи
Soviet Union, yes And these territories are
Советского Союза да А эти территории ещё
lagging behind even more because,
больше отстают потому что
uh, the Soviet Union kept people in poverty, kept them
ээ совок держал людей в бедности держал
in hopelessness, if it were possible to leave the Soviet Union,
в безысходности если бы в совке можно
people would have left the Soviet Union even then. Yes, there would be
было уезжать люди бы из Совка ещё тогда
no one left there,
бы уехали Да никого бы там не осталось
that’s why  when Russians say that
вот поэтому когда русские говорят что
they are leaving, they are leaving, of course they are leaving countries,
уезжают уезжают конечно уезжают из стран
people are always going to some
всегда люди едут в какие-то более
richer countries Yes, they are looking for better
богатые страны Да ищут лучших
economic conditions This is a normal
экономических условий Это нормальный
process Yes, it is extended
процесс Да он растянутый
historically over time, yes But if the
исторически во времени да Но если
Soviet Union made a barrier, the
Советский Союз делал барьер барьер
barrier is such an iron barrier And then this
барьер такой железный А потом этот
barrier broke through  Of course, it went the same way
барьер прорвал конечно это пошло так же
as in the villages they kept
как в сёлах держали держали насильно
people in the villages by force, they didn’t let them out then the
людей в сёлах не выпускали потом
Soviet Union collapsed Yes, people from the villages quietly
Советский Союз рухнул Да из сёл спокойно
began to move to the cities, a sharp
начали переезжать в города резкий
surge in
всплеск
real estate Yes, why did I go
на недвижимость Да почему пошёл потому
because there was not enough
что стало не хватать в
housing in the cities because this is the process of
городах жилья потому что вот это процесс
urbanization that  should have happened
урбанизации который должен был проходить
gradually Yes, he rushed due to the fact that
постепенно Да он рванул из-за того что
he was restrained like this and here the Russians,
его сдерживали так и тут и россияне они
instead of thinking about How to be
вместо того чтобы думать Как самим быть
richer themselves Yes, but he doesn’t think about how I
богаче Да как вот он не думает как мне
can make sure that my minimum wage
сделать чтобы у меня зарплата минима
is the same as in Estonia, Latvia,  In
была такая как в Эстонии в Латвии в
Lithuania, he doesn’t think about how to make
Литве он не думает Как сделать
sure that the standard of living is the same, he thinks
скажем уровень жизни был он думает
communal apartment, communal apartment, it feels
коммуналка вот коммуналка такое ощущение
like when they always talk about
что они вот они когда всегда говорят про
communal apartments, they have a feeling in their head
коммуналку у них такое ощущение в голове
that a resident of Europe is getting a salary,
что житель Европы вот получает зарплату
paid taxes and paid everything else for the
выплатил налоги и остальное всё отдал за
communal apartment and sits sucking  paw has nothing to
коммуналку и сидит сосёт лапу нечего
eat
кушать
and the problem is not that they are so
и проблема не в том что они вот такие
poor
бедные
and the problem is that they want to drag others into their own
и проблема в том что они хотят в своё
This swamp Come on
Вот это болото затянуть других Давай
Latvia we will return you you left illegally
Латвия мы вернём вас вы незаконно вышли
Ukraine We are one people
Украина Мы один народ
they are all moved in like this Because if
все них вселяются такие Потому что если
you develop If you  the
вы развиваете Если вы
cool ones, on the contrary, they want to be friends with
крутые наоборот с вами хотят дружить с
you, they want to integrate If we
Вами хотят интегрироваться Если мы
look Yes, it’s the same Europe there
смотрим Да там тот же самый Европа там
Kato Germany Britain France they are
Като Германия Британия Франция они
developing, then everyone wants to be with them and
развиваются то все хотят с ними быть а
they already think no, let us not you
они уже думаю нене давайте мы вас не
Why the European Union Yes, we are still asking for that
Почему Евросоюз Да мы ещё просим в тот
European Union  let's take us, they
Евросоюз давайте давайте нас берите они
don't Wait, let's first make
не Подождите давайте вы сначала сделаете
such reforms like that yes, that is, it is
такие реформы такие такие да то есть
clear that But we need We want to go there
видно что Но нам нужно Мы хотим туда
because there are certain standards Yes,
потому что там определённые стандарты Да
and the European Union is already expressing some
и Евросоюз уже высказывает какие-то
conditions But in Russia, on the contrary, they are doing so
условия А в России наоборот у них так
well well but  no one wants to come to them
хорошо хорошо но никто к ним не хохочет
and they forcefully drag everyone in. What
и они силой всех затягивают Что же это
kind of paradise is this, that you need to pull strength there?
такой за рай что туда нужно тянуть силы
Let's like squeak comment subscribe to
Давайте лайк писка комент подпишись на
my Instagram I don't know why this is
мий Instagram Я не знаю для чего це тоб
why you are there to marvel at this face
Для чего тоб там дивитись на оце й фейс
Ale for you this is one  two or three clicks
Але для тебе це один два або три клика
Ale you are trime me and I will be kaza Wow in
Але ты тримае мене и я буду каза Вау в
me there Kupa fouls and in me there will be a
мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
classy mood to robiti but cool video
класний настрий щоб робити но крут вдео
message on th Instagram pop Andriy
пись на й Instagram попк Андрий вот
like this let me
так давай я тебя
check for you and
чекаю а